If you are starting out in the field of finance and
如果你刚刚踏入金融行业
you ask any experienced portfolio manager,
并且询问任何有经验的投资组合经理
investment banker or research analyst for advice on how to improve your skills,
投资银行家或研究分析师如何提高技能
it's very likely that one of their suggestions would be to read financial news.
很有可能他们会建议你阅读财经新闻
Most people working in financial services read
供职于金融行业的大部分人
financial and business news regularly in order to stay in touch with the markets.
都会定期阅读财经和商业新闻 从而掌握市场最新动态
Watch for trends and look out for unexpected events that may affect their portfolios.
观察走势并留意可能会影响投资组合的意外事件
The rise of social media has created
社交媒体的诞生
another source that we can use to measure the pulse of the markets.
使我们能够通过另一途径把握市场脉搏
For example, negative tweets about accompany whether thereby investors, or customers,
例如 关于公司的负面推文 无论是由投资者还是客户发布的
may provide a lead for investors signaling that it may be
都可以向投资者提供交易信号
a good idea to follow up and analyze that stock in more detail.
表明应该持续关注并详细分析该股票
Companies that receive lots of positive attention from both news,
不断收到新闻 媒体和社交媒体正面报道的公司
media and social media may have a higher chance of being over bought.
的股票更有可能被炒高
As much of the general public hear as positive mentions about a particular company,
当很多人都听到关于某家公司的正面新闻后
they may also jump in to buy the stock hoping to
他们可能会买入该股票
ride the wave of a stock that appears to just keep going up.
希望能跟着不断上涨的股票走势获利
This may push the stock to a price that's above what's supported by fundamentals.
这样可能会将股价推动到高于受基本面支撑的股价
At which point the stock may be a potential candidate to short sell.
这时候股票可能就可以列入卖空候选名单了
Notice how we don't have to assume that every news article or
注意 我们不用认为每篇报道或社交媒体帖子
a social media post is the definitive truth about the health of a company.
都是关于公司运营状况的绝对真实报道
This data is really measuring the sentiment of people whether they're investors,
这些数据体现的是人们的情绪
customers, or public figures with lots of followers.
无论是投资者 客户还是有很多关注者的公众人物
Financial analysts have been applying natural language processing or
金融分析师一直都在对新闻和社交媒体
NLP on news and social media to analyze public sentiment towards companies.
运用自然语言处理 (NLP) 来分析公众对公司的情绪
In other words, they're trying to turn raw text into
他们尝试将原始文本变成一种信号
a signal about whether people have a positive or negative view of a stock's future.
表示人们对股票的未来保持正面或负面观点
This is similar to tracking the sentiment of financial research analysts
这种情绪分析与金融研究分析师的情绪分析类似
except with news and social media there isn't always a clearly labeled buy,
但是对于新闻和社交媒体来说 并非始终都存在清晰的
hold or sell rating.
买入 持有或卖出评级
NLP can be used to estimate how likely
NLP 可以估测
a news article blog post or social media posts can be categorized as buy, hold or sell.
新闻报道 博客帖子或社交媒体帖子被分类为买入 持有或卖出的概率是多少
In term two of this program,
在这门课程的第二学期
you will learn how to use NLP and deep learning to analyze
你将学习如何使用 NLP 和深度学习
social media data and apply these skills in order to generate Alpha factors.
分析社交媒体数据 并利用这些技能生成 Alpha 因子